你们在干什么
What are you guys doing up?
我们想填完字谜再去睡觉
Oh, we wanted to finish the crossword before we went to bed.
你知不知道  六个字母的表示红色的词
Hey, do you know a six-letter word for red?
深红色
Dark red.
应该不是
Yeah, I think that's wrong,
不过你待会可以玩连点画图
but there's a Connect the Dots in here for you later.
褐红色呢
Hey, how about maroon?
没错  你好聪明
Yes, you are so smart!
你们好可爱哦
Aww, you guys are so cute!
我知道
I know.
-好了  明天早上见  -好的
- All right, I'll see you in the morning. - Okay.
亲爱的  我最喜欢跟你玩填字谜了
Y'know, I love doing crossword puzzles with you honey!
我也是  赶快填完去睡觉吧
Aww, me too. Now let's finish this and go to bed.
好  只剩一个了
Okay! There's only one left,
三个字母的单词  不是小狗  是...
three letter word, not dog but...
猫咪
Cat.
没错  你好聪明
Yes! You are so smart!
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
还差小费
Uhh, we still need a tip.
好  等等
All right. Hold on.
有了
I got it.
五分钱  还差多少
Nickel! How much more do we need?
差几块
A couple of bucks.
一毛
Okay, dime!
你们继续聊  我要花一点时间
You guys should probably keep talking; this could take a while.
等等  你们看
Oh no, wait! Look it! Whoa!
天哪  这是警徽
Oh my God, this is a police badge!
真酷  但警察来这里干嘛
Oh that's so cool! Why would a cop come in here though?
这里又不卖甜甜圈
They don't serve donuts.
你能不能重来一次
Y'know what actually, could you discover the badge again?
我可以说个更好笑的
I think I can come up with something better than that.
菲比  肯定有人正在找那个警徽
Phoebe, I bet somebody's missing that badge.
没错  我应该送回去
Yeah, I should probably take it back.
知道吗  我去了警察局
Ooh, but you know what? While I'm at the police station,
还可以看看十大通缉犯名单
I could check their Ten Most Wanted lists
我朋友弗丽西一直是排十一
because my friend Fritzy has been like number 11 forever,
她今年也许会走运
so this could be her year!
大家好
Hey, you guys!
乔伊
Hey Joey!
那是我的运动衫吗
That uh, that my sweatshirt?
对  抱歉  我很冷就借来穿了
Oh yes, it is. I'm sorry I borrowed it, I was cold.
没关系吧
I hope its okay?
只是  你知道的
Well uh, it's just that uh, y'know if-
如果你要穿别人的运动衫
if you're gonna be wearing someone's sweatshirt
应该穿你男朋友的吧
shouldn't it be your boyfriends--
我不是你的男朋友
and I'm not him.
对不起  我现在就还你
I'm sorry, I'll give it back to you.
不要  上面沾满了你的味道
No-no! No! I mean it's gonna be all smelling like Monica!
你是说我很臭吗
Are you saying I smell bad?
不是  你有一股青草香
No! No, you smell like a meadow.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他是怎么了
What's with him?
乔伊上次去青草地
Oh, y'know what? The last time Joey went to a meadow,
他老娘被猎人射杀了
his mother was shot by a hunter.
我还是不确定
Yeah, I still don't know.
抱歉  我只是想买到理想的沙发
I'm sorry I just wanna make sure that I bought the right couch.
我希望这张沙发能表示
I need a couch that says,
"欢迎你们  小朋友"
"Kids welcome here."
同时也能让人觉得  "来我身边吧"
But that also says,  "Come here to me!"
什么  你对小朋友说那种话吗
What?! You say that to kids?!!
不是  "来我身边吧"是对女士们说的
No! No! No! The "Come here to me" is y'know for the ladies.
罗斯  这是张好沙发  但不是神奇沙发
Ross, honey, it's a nice couch. It's not a magic couch.
你的选择很正确
You picked a great couch.
是吗
Yeah?
没错  请在这里签个名
Yeah. Could you just sign right here please?
没问题
Oh, sure.
这是...
Whoa-whoa, what's this?
送货费几乎跟沙发价格一样贵
The delivery charge is almost as much as the couch!
太荒谬了
Wait! No, that's ridiculous.
他家离这里才三条街
Come on, he lives three blocks away!
算了  我自己搬就好  谢谢
Yeah, y'know what? I'll take it myself, thank you!
-瑞秋  来吧  咱们走  -好的
- All right Rach, come on, let's go! - Yeah!
开什么玩笑
Are you kiddin'?
拜托  才三条街
Oh, come on it's only three blocks!
又不是很重  抬抬看  快
And-and, it's not very heavy, try it! Come on! Come on!
我搬得动耶
Oh. Oh! I can do it!
你们会很喜欢这张沙发的
You two are really gonna enjoy that couch.
我们不是一对
Oh yeah, we're uh, yeah we're not together.
好吧  难怪我觉得怪怪的
Ohh, okay.  Something didn't quite add up there.
罗斯
Ross!
-这话是什么意思  -罗斯
- What's that supposed to mean? - Ross!
你  她
Well you, her,
她很...  你知道的
I mean, she's very...y'know.
而你却...  你知道的
And you're like...y'know.
虽然与你无关  但我们确实交往过
Not that it's any of your business, but we did go out.
-真的  你们两个  -是的  瑞秋
- Really? You two? - Yeah! Rach?
我现在不想讲这个
Come on, I don't really want to be doing this right now.
我抬着一张很重的沙发
I am carrying a very heavy couch.
那就赶快告诉他
Then tell him quickly.
好  我们交往过
Fine!  We went out.
不只交往过
Not only did we go out,
还做过298次
we did it 298 times!
罗斯
Ross!!
天哪  你居然还计了数
Oh my--ugh!! You kept count?!
你真没用
You are such a loser!
再没用你也做了298次
A loser you did it with 298 times!
-打扰下  女士  -什么事
- Oh. Oh! Ma'am? Excuse me, ma'am? - Yes?
你不能在树上灭香烟
You can't put your cigarette out on a tree!
我可以  很方便
Yeah I can, it worked real well.
你不该这么做  别再这么做了
No but you shouldn't! So don't ever do that again.
我不会了  抽下一根烟之前不会
I won't! Until I have my next cigarette.
站住  纽约警局  不许动  混混
Hold it! N.Y.P.D! Freeze punk!
什么
What?!
没错  你被抓了个现行
Yeah that's right you are so busted.
做笔录
Book 'em.
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking too?
别挣扎了  红发妞
Save it Red!
不想在牢里过夜
Unless you wanna spend the night in the slammer,
就跟那棵树道歉
you apologize to the tree.
我才不会跟一棵树道歉
I am not going to apologize to a tree!
赶快道歉  否则我要叫支援了
You apologize to the tree right now or I am calling for backup.
支援  支援
Backup! Backup!!
对不起  对不起
I-I'm sorry! Sorry.
支援别来了  别来了
Okay, cancel backup! Cancel backup!
罗斯  你不是说有电梯吗
Ross, didn't you say that there was an elevator in here?
我是说有  但其实没有  来吧
Uhh, yes I did but there isn't. Okay, here we go.
往左  左  左
Okay, go left. Left! Left!
已经没有左了
Okay, y'know what? There is no more left, left!
好的  抬到你头上
Oh okay, lift it straight up over your head!
抬到你的头上
Straight up over your head!
你行的  你行的
You can do it! You can do it!
没问题吧
Okay. You got it?
很好
Good-good-good.
没问题吧  没问题吧  行吗
Yeah, you got it right? You got it right? You got it?
你觉得放在那里好看吗
Any chance you think the couch looks good there?
这家伙还这样
...so this guy was all
我就说凶案组布菲
And I'm all, Buffay, Homicide.
真是酷毙了
It was just so cool!
菲比  你应该拿去还的
Phoebe, you were supposed to take that back!
我知道  但做好事的感觉好棒
I know but I'm having so much fun doing good deeds.
但假扮警察很严重
Okay, but impersonating a police officer is a serious thing.
你会被抓的
You could get arrested.
你现在就会被抓
You could get arrested, right now!
我得拿去还
All right, yeah, I gotta take it back.
我被权力冲昏头了
I'm totally drunk with power.
乔伊
Hi, Joe.
我不知道你们会在
Yeah, I didn't know you guys were going to be here.
乔伊  帮个忙  你尝尝看
Hey Joey, do me a favor, sweetie, taste this.
什么  为什么
What?! Why?!
你是怎么了
What is going on with you?
没事啊
Nothing!
拜托  你一整天都怪怪的
Oh, come on! You've been acting strange all day!
好吧  是有一件事
All right! There is something.
我做了一个梦
I kinda had a dream,
但我不想谈
but I don't want to talk about it.
马丁·路德金也这么说还得了
Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-what-what if Martin Luther King had said that?
我有一个梦
I kinda have a dream!
但是我不想谈
I don't want to talk about it.
跟莫妮卡有关
Well, it involved Monica.
你梦到我正在交往的女孩
You had a dream about a girl that I am seeing?!
真酷  我不知梦见过
Oh, that is so cool!  I can't tell you how many times
他的女朋友多少次了
I've dreamt about a girl that he was seeing.
总之我们在谈你的梦
Anyway we're talking about your dream.
我爱你  你的梦
I love you. Your dream?
放心  没有任何色情内容
Don't worry, there wasn't any sex in it or anything.
自从发现你们的事后
I haven't dreamt about her like that
我就不对她做那种梦了
since I found out about you two--ish.
那你梦到什么
What was the dream about?
好吧
Well, okay.
你是我的女朋友  我们在填字谜
You were my girlfriend and we were doing the crossword puzzle.
就像你们昨晚那样
Y'know like you guys were doing last night.
就这样  我爱上莫妮卡了  我会搬走
So, that's it. I'm in love with Monica and I'll be moving out.
乔伊  等等
Wait, Joey! Joey!
那并不代表你爱我
That doesn't mean that-that you're in love with me!
不是吗
It-it doesn't?
可能有很多含义
No, it can mean anything.
例如  你突然眼红
Like uh, all of the sudden you're jealous
我成为这里的猛男
because I've become the apartment stud.
听起来比较像你的梦  老兄
That kinda sounds like your dream dude.
或许你看到我和钱德勒
Or, it could mean that-that you saw Chandler and me together
在一起很亲密
and we y'know were being close and stuff
你也想跟别人拥有这种关系
and then you just want to have that with someone too.
我在梦里的确很享受那种亲密
In the dream I did enjoy the closeness.
你对莫妮卡有兴趣吗
are you attracted to Monica?
就说此时此刻吧  你对莫妮卡有兴趣吗
Right here, right now, are you attracted to her?
没有
Not really.
这就对了
Well there you have it!
当然啦  我穿得这么休闲
Well sure! I'm just wearing sweats!
但这是好事  你不是爱我
But that's good that you're not in love with me,
你只是想交个女朋友
because you just want a girlfriend!
我觉得不是交女朋友的问题
No, I don't think it's just about just getting a girlfriend.
我可以找个女朋友
Y'know? I mean, yeah, I can get a girlfriend!
我们可以坐在那里填字谜
Yeah, we could sit in the chair and do crosswords,
但我们会拥有
but y'know are we ever going to have
你们那种亲密吗
y'know the closeness like-like you guys have?
莫妮卡和我在恋爱前就是朋友
Well y'know, Monica and I were friends before we started dating.
也许关键在这里
So maybe-maybe that's it?
先做朋友  有意思
Friends first? That's interesting.
你们都事后当朋友吗
You become friends after?
也从来没有过
No, never done that either.
你们有卷尺吗
Hey, umm, do you guys have that tape measure?
有  在我房里
Oh yeah, it's actually in my bedroom.
没错
That's right.
乔伊  怎么了
What's up Joey?
你好吗
How you doin'?
抱歉  这是你的车吗
Excuse me, is this your car?
对
Yeah.
停在这里不太好
Well I don't think it's very nice of you to park here,
你挡住出入口了
y'know you're blocking the entrance.
放心  没关系的
Don't worry about it. It's not a problem.
我觉得有关系
Well, it's a problem for me,
你就有关系  因为我是警察
which means it's a problem for you 'cause I'm a cop.
我也是
So am I!
不好
No.
好吧  你是警察  可以任意停车
Oh okay, so you're a cop which means you can park anywhere,
这个我知道  因为我也是警察
'cause I know that 'cause I'm a cop too.
好的  继续努力  收到
So, all right, keep up the good work. 10-4.
等一下  你是哪个分局的
Hey, wait a second! So wait, what precinct are you with?
我在57分局
I-I'm with the umm, the 57th.
我认识你们凶案组一位警察
Oh, I know a guy in homicide up there.
我在扫黄组
I'm in vice.
事实上我正在卧底  我是妓女
Yeah, in fact I'm undercover right now. I'm a whore.
扫黄组还有谁
Who-who else is in vice up there?
你认识西波威兹吗(《纽约重案组》人物)
Umm, do you know, umm Sipowicz?
西波威兹  应该不认识
Sipowicz? No, I don't think so.
西波威兹  大块头  有点秃
Yeah, Sipowicz, big guy, kinda bald.
我不认识他
No, I don't know him.
不要打电话给他
Don't try to call him or anything,
他不在  他出去了
'cause he's not there, he's out.
他的拍档刚死了
His umm, his partner just died.
请帮我向西波威兹转达慰问
Wow umm, tell Sipowicz I'm real sorry for his loss.
我会的  保重
I-I sure will, take care.
对了  我相信西波威兹不会有事的
Hey by the way, I'm sure Sipowicz is gonna be all right.
听说新来的  原来出演《银匙》的小伙子很不错
I heard that kid from Silver Spoons is really good.
你在哪里找到我的警徽的
And where did you find my badge?
乔伊  你能不能帮我和罗斯搬沙发
Hey! Joey, would you mind giving me and Ross a hand moving his couch?
我很想  但我要去上表演课
Oh, I'd love too, but I got acting class.
不过我可以为了你翘课
But y'know what? I guess I can blow that off,  for you.
-多谢  -瑞秋  我问你一件事
- Thanks! - Uh, hey, Rach let me ask you something.
我刚在对面跟莫妮卡和钱德勒聊天
Uh, I was just over there talking to Monica and Chandler,
他们可真亲密
boy they are really tight.
是啊
I know.
那种关系实在很不错
Yeah that's not such a bad situation they got going over there.
我也想自己弄一段
I'm thinking of getting me one of those.
乔伊  你想说什么
What's up Joe?
我觉得他们感觉会那么好
Well, the reason I think Monica and Chandler are so great...
是因为他们是先做朋友
...is because they were friends first.
于是我问自己  谁是我朋友
Y'know? So I asked myself, "Who are my friends?"
你和菲比  而我先遇见你  所以...
You and Phoebe, and I saw you first. So...
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我是说也许你我可以更进一步
I'm saying maybe you and I crank it up a notch.
亲爱的  我真是受宠若惊
Y'know honey, umm, as uh, as flattered as I am that uh,
你先遇见我
you saw me first,
但我不觉得我们应该更进一步
uhh, I just, I-I don't think we should be cranking anything up.
我会对你很好的
I'll treat you real nice.
你知道吗
Yeah, well, y'know umm...
我觉得先做朋友再交往
No honey, listen I think it's a great idea to become friends
是一个很好的想法
with someone before you date them,
但你应该先去认识一个人
but I think the way you do it is y'know you meet someone,
跟她做朋友  建立基础
become their friend, build a foundation,
再约她出去
then you ask them out on a date.
别对现有的朋友下手
Don't hit on your existing friends!
那不是要很久吗
Won't-won't that take longer?
没错  但是一旦找到
Yeah. Yeah. Oh, but once you find it,
等待就是值得的
ohh it's so worth the wait.
我懂  我懂
Yeah. I understand. I understand.
真希望先遇见菲比
Man, I wish I saw Phoebe first!
来我身边吧
Come here to me.
不  你来我身边
No-no, you come here to me.
罗斯
Hey Ross!
我带援军来了
I brought reinforcements.
太好了  是乔伊吗
Oh great! What, you brought Joey?
只比他差一点
Well, I brought the next best thing.
钱德勒  你带钱德勒来
Chandler?! You brought Chandler?!
只差一点的是莫妮卡
The next best thing would be Monica!
我应该要不爽  但莫妮卡真的壮得可怕
Y'know, I would be offended, but Monica is freakishly strong, so...
我画了一张搬运草图
Look, I-I drew a sketch about how we're gonna do it. Okay
瑞秋  这是你  这是沙发
Rach,  that's you. That's the couch.
那是什么
Whoa-oh, what's-what's that?
那是我
Oh, that's me.
你把自己看得很雄壮
You certainly think a lot of yourself.
不  那是我的手臂
No! That's-that's my arm!
懂了  我还以为你好爱你的新沙发
Oh, I see. I thought you just really, really liked your new couch.
-总之听我的指示  -好的
- Y'know what? Just-just follow my lead. - Okay!
钱德勒  来吧
Come on, Chandler.
好了  走吧
All right. Okay, here we go!
好  准备好了吗
All right, ready?
可以
Yeah.
-转  -好的
- Turn. - Okay.
转  转
Turn! Turn!
应该是转不动了
Okay, I don't think we can turn anymore!
罗斯  我觉得挤不过去
Ross, I don't, I just don't think it's going to fit.
当然可以  快抬起来
Oh yeah it will! Come on, up! Up-up-up!
抬起来  很好  可以了  绕轴转动
Up! Yes! Here we go! Pivot!
绕轴转动
Pivot!
Piv-ot!
绕轴转动
Piv-et!!
Piv-ett!!!
绕轴转动
Piv-et!
闭嘴  闭嘴  闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!!
我看是转不动了
Okay, I don't think it's going to pivot anymore.
是吗
You think?!
搬下去再来一次
All right, let's uh, let's bring it back down and-and try again.
现在真的卡死了
Okay, yeah, I think it's really stuck now.
居然不行
I can't believe that didn't work!
就是啊  你都画了图了
I know, me neither! I mean, you had a sketch!
你说绕轴转动是什么意思
Oh, y'know, what did you mean when you said pivot?
怎样  有交到新朋友吗
Hey! How's it going? Did you make any new friends?
有  我认识了一个女人
Yeah, yeah, I met this woman.
等等  她怎么样
Hey, whoa-whoa! What's she like?
她的床上功夫很棒
Uhh, well, she's...really good in bed.
乔伊  你不是要先做朋友吗
Joey, I thought you were gonna try to be friends first!
都是你的错
Well look, hey, it's all your fault!
为什么啊
What?! Why?!
你没有给我忠告
Well because you didn't give me advice!
你告诉我的是搭讪词
No! You gave me a pickup line!
我一说要
As soon as I told her I wanted to
建立基础  先做朋友
y'know, build a foundation and be friends first.
突然间  错不在我啊
I suddenly, through no fault of my own,
她就觉得我难以抗拒了
became irresistible to her!
她的室友也是
And her roommate!
那亲密关系呢
What about the closeness?
不亲密才怪  我们有三个人啊
Closeness-shmoshness! There was three of us for crying out loud!
谁要吃披萨
All right! Hey, who wants pizza?!
我要
Ooh, I do! I do! I do!
太棒了  这是我在二楼捡到的
Oh, great! Can you believe I found it on the second floor?
哪一位
Who is it?
纽约警局
N.Y.P.D!!
天哪
Oh my God!
等一下  警察先生
Uhh, just a minute officer!!
我要找菲比·布菲
I'm looking for Phoebe Buffay!
完了  是那个警察
Ooh, God, it's him! It's that cop!
他居然找到我了
God, I can't believe it! He found me!
天哪  菲比  你会坐牢吗
Oh my God, Phoebe, are you gonna go to jail?!
我要死也要拖你们下水
Well, if I'm going down, you guys are going down with me.
窝藏逃犯  起码要关一到三年
Harboring a fugitive? That's one to three years minimum.
钱德勒  祝你好运
Good luck Chandler.
好吧  你可以逮捕我
Okay, you can arrest me.
但你抓不到我的把柄  你知道的
Fine. But you'll never make it stick and you know it!
但我别无选择
Yeah, but I kinda don't have a choice,
这是职责所在  你了解吧
it's my job. I mean, you understand right?
只要你了解  我会找我的律师来
Yep! As long as you understand that I'm going to call my lawyer
他会让你在庭上像个猪头
and once he puts you on the stand he'll make you look like a fool.
猪头
A fool!
我不喜欢当猪头
I don't like looking foolish.
这样吧  我今天不抓你
Y'know what? Maybe uh, I don't arrest you today.
我来了  但你不在
Maybe I came by and you weren't here.
我不在就太好了
I would love it if I weren't here!
既然你今晚不会入狱
Okay, so since umm, you're not going to jail tonight
我能不能请你去吃饭
I was wondering if you would like to go to dinner with me?
我
Me?!
自从你对我亮警徽
Yeah. Ever since you flashed my badge at me,
我就对你念念不忘
I kinda can't stop thinking about you.
你是我见过最美的假卧底妓女
You're the prettiest, fake undercover whore I've ever seen.
漂亮
Nice!
我真的没想到
Wow! I didn't see that coming!
你会约我出去
You're-you're asking me out!
我可以表现得更好
Yeah. I mean, I coulda done it better,
但这些人一直盯着我
but these people keep staring at me.
我愿意跟你吃饭  警官
Umm, yeah, I'd like to go out with you officer...
盖瑞
Gary.
这就是约会了
Okay, so it's a date.
好的  不过我一定要问
Yeah! So--ooh, I gotta ask you though.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you know where to find me?
我的警徽上都是你的指纹
Well you're fingerprints were all over my badge
我上电脑查询
so I just ran it through the computer
这是你最后登记的住址
and this was listed as your last known address
所以我就来看看
so I just checked it out.
好厉害
Ohh, impressive.
没有你厉害  我看过你的记录
Not as impressive as you. I gotta tell you, I looked at your record
你干过不少怪事
and you've done some pretty weird stuff.
-吃饭时再说  -好
- Yeah, we'll talk at dinner. - Okay.
我几小时后来接你好吗
So I'll come by in a couple hours and pick you up?
好啊  我好激动
All right, I can't wait!
放心  我不会只带你吃甜甜圈的
Okay. And don't worry, I'm not just gonna take you out for donuts.
他有枪
He has a gun!
我要退这张沙发  我对它不满意
I'd like to return this couch. I'm not satisfied with it.
你要退这张沙发
You wanna return this couch?
它断成两半了
It's cut in half!
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm telling you.
是你把它弄成两半的吗
Did you cut this couch in half?
这张沙发断成两半
This couch, is cut in half!
我要换一张没有断成两半的
I would like to exchange it for one that is not cut in half!
你是说沙发送去时就这样了
You're telling me this couch was delivered to you like this?!
我很讲道理  我愿意接受换购金额
Look, I am a reasonable man. I will accept store credit.
我给你四块的换购金额
I'll give you store credit in the amount of four dollars.
我接受
I will take it.